<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Aditya Shrey</title>
    <link>https://aditya-shrey.github.io/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Aditya Shrey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.125.4</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 15:01:10 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://aditya-shrey.github.io/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Melanoma Detection: A Comparative Study of Machine Learning Techniques Using the Melanoma Skin Cancer Dataset</title>
      <link>https://aditya-shrey.github.io/projects/3-ml-melanoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 15:01:10 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aditya-shrey.github.io/projects/3-ml-melanoma/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Early detection of melanoma skin cancer is critical for effective treatment. In this study, we compare machine learning techniques, including CNNs, SVMs, Logistic Regression, and Transfer Learning with ResNet-18, using the Melanoma Skin Cancer Dataset. Through pre-processing and hyperparameter optimization, we assess model performance in terms of accuracy, precision, recall, and F1-score. Our findings highlight CNNs’ efficacy in achieving high accuracy, with SVM and Transfer Learning also showing promise. This study contributes to advancing machine learning applications in medical imaging for melanoma detection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous Taxi System within a Simulated City Environment</title>
      <link>https://aditya-shrey.github.io/projects/2-av-proj/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 15:01:10 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aditya-shrey.github.io/projects/2-av-proj/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Our immersion project focused on developing an autonomous taxi system within a simulated miniature city environment. We programmed a virtual taxi to navigate this environment autonomously, relying solely on raw sensor measurements (e.g., GPS, IMU) and the bounding box output of object detection algorithms. The core challenge involved achieving robust perception and localization, allowing the taxi to understand its surroundings and precisely determine its position within the map. This perception data then fueled dynamic routing and motion planning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grants Self Service System</title>
      <link>https://aditya-shrey.github.io/projects/1-dsi-spa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 15:01:10 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aditya-shrey.github.io/projects/1-dsi-spa/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Grants-Self-Service project represents a transformative step in managing the grant application process at Vanderbilt University. This pioneering initiative utilizes advanced generative AI, including private, institutional AI instances and innovative techniques like retrieval augmented generation (RAG) and custom GPT models. Our aim is to simplify and accelerate grant development and submission, enabling faculty to swiftly access and efficiently handle vast repositories of prior grant data, which include over 479,980 previously submitted grants.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
